Barry Lim

Solution Architect / Developer

Barry Lim

+65 97376671

barlim3@yahoo.com.sg

http://www.linkedin.com/pub/barry-lim/3/790/bb3

https://vimeo.com/135264568

Summary

I have been in the Media for over a decade, constantly updating both my creative and technical skills. My biggest strength is adaptability, I learn and adapt fast to various work environments. I always look forward to challenging issues in production and seek to optimize the efficiency while maintaining a high quality. Recent years have seen me take on roles of Project management and organization management roles, while also implementing technological infrastructures strategies and solution planning for overall systems

Skills

Python ◆ Postgres SQL ◆ CSS ◆ HTML ◆ Javascript ◆ R ◆ Unix ◆ SQL ◆ VFX & CG Production ◆ Front-end development ◆ DevOps ◆ Backend Development ◆ Organizational Management ◆ Budgeting ◆ Project and Resource Planning ◆ Git ◆ SVN ◆ Data Analytics ◆ C#

Experience

Ubisoft Singapore / Senior Technical Animator

MAY 2021 - PRESENT, SINGAPORE

- Managing of animated asset integration to proprietary game engine
- Maintenance and development of semi-automated the pipeline process across Houdini, 3ds max, Motion Builder and Anvil. Languages used; Python, Maxscript, Houdini VEX and C#.
- Cloth simulations in Houdini
- Projects worked on: Skulls & Bones

Omens Studios / VFX & CG Supervisor

FEBRUARY 2019 - APRIL 2021, SINGAPORE

- VFX and CG supervisor managing projects across multiple facilities
- Manage Project Technicals and quality
- Organizational management of production
- Manages IT and Technology development team
- Solution Architect and developer for company-wide internal asset management system.
- Assist in overseeing and planning for IT department.
- Manages Development and Operations of technology

Experience

10 Dimensions Studios / CG Supervisor & Animation Director

JUNE 2018 - JANUARY 2019, BEIJING

- Manage CG department
- Manage project and client relations
- Developed IT solutions for company.
- Implement network "Air Gap".
- Solution Architect and developer for production pipeline
- IT support and script development in Python

Digital Domain / CG Supervisor & Animation Director

OCTOBER 2017 - MAY 2018, BEIJING

- CG supervisor managing projects
- Manage Project Technicals and quality
- Manages Technology development team
- Solution Architect and developer for production pipeline
- Handled the creative direction for animation in production
- Manages Development and Operations of technology
- Providing script development in Python

Red Dragon Media Ltd / Animation Director

DECEMBER 2016 - AUGUST 2017, BEIJING

- Manage Animation production
- Handled the creative direction for animation in production
- Solution Architect and Developer for production pipeline
- Providing IT support and script development in Python

VHQ / CG Supervisor & Animation Supervisor

OCTOBER 2015 - NOVEMBER 2016, BEIJING

- CG supervisor managing projects across multiple facilities
- Supervised 100+ man team of artist for production
- Solution Architect and Developer for production pipeline
- Handled the creative direction for animation in production
- Providing IT support and script development in Python

CGCG Inc / Supervising Lead Animator

OCTOBER 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2015, XIAMEN

- Manage Animation production
- Handled the creative direction for animation in production
- Worked on animation for production

3Dsense Media School / Lecturer

OCTOBER 2012 - SEPTEMBER 2014, SINGAPORE

- Developed Diploma curriculum for Animation and Rigging
- Supervised students Final Short film development
- Solution Architect for student work environment

Experience

Drawiz Inc / Lead Animator

FEBRUARY 2013 - AUGUST 2014, SINGAPORE

- Manage an internal Animation team for production
- Handled the creative direction for animation in production
- Worked on animation for production
- Solution Architect for animation production pipeline.

ILM Singapore / Animator & Assistant TD

NOVEMBER 2006 - SEPTEMBER 2012, SINGAPORE

- Worked on animation shots for Animated Features, Animated Series and VFX productions.
- Created and automated the QC of final layout department.
- Troubleshoot production issues.
- Manage backend system farm resources and render jobs.
- Assisted the pipeline development for production.

Education

National University of Singapore / Degree in Computing with Honours in Communications and Media

JULY 2002 - JUNE 2006, SINGAPORE

Developed a Fur Grooming Maya plugin

Used Fly3D Game Engine to develop a 1st person shooter

3Dsense Media School / Diploma in Digital Visual Effects and Animation

JANUARY 2006 - DECEMBER 2006, SINGAPORE

Specialized in Character Animation

Animation Mentor / Diploma in Advance Studies in Character Animation

JANUARY 2008 - JUNE 2009, USA

Online professional school taken while under employment

Certifications

Jedi Training Program in Character Animation

Wiley Certified Data Analyst

Artificial Intelligence Analyst - Explorer Award 2019

Artificial Intelligence Analyst - Mastery Award 2019

DevOps Fundamentals

Certified Blockchain Specialist